For honor. For justice. For freedom.
Medieval is a action, drama, history film directed by Petr Jákl.
The story of fifteenth century Czech icon and warlord, Jan Zizka, who
defeated armies of the Teutonic Order and the Holy Roman Empire.
Jan Žižka, played by Ben Foster.
Kateřina, played by Sophie Lowe.
Lord Boreš, played by Michael Caine.
Torak, played by Roland Møller.
Lars, played by Magnus Samuelsson.
Rožmberk, played by Til Schweiger.
Medieval (Jan Žižka or Warrior of God) is a 2022 English-language
Czech historical drama film directed by Petr Jákl.
It is about the life of Jan Žižka, a Bohemian
military commander who never lost a battle.
The film is set prior to the Hussite Wars (1419–1434), when Žižka was young.
It tells the story of how Žižka became a famous military commander.
With a budget of KČ500 million ($20.3 million), it is
the most expensive Czech film ever made.
the film was released on September 8, 2022.
The film divided critics
The film explores themes of based on true story, middle ages
(476-1453), medieval, 15th century, hussite wars (1419-1434).
The tone is emotional.